Guide to the Allison Davis Papers 1932-1984
University of Chicago Library
- Series V: Research Files
  - Subseries 5: Child-rearing in Lower Status Families
    - Sub-subseries 2: Newbury Center Material
      - Child-rearing practices, tables, charts, notes, 1943-44, Child-rearing practices, data sheets--Negro, undated SEE Box 87, Folder 1 (OVERSIZE) (Box 37, Folder 14)
      - "Rules of Evidence," outline, bibliography, notes, undated (Box 37, Folder 15)
      - Community notes, Newbury Center interviews, T. S. Downs, [Ms.] Cooper, 1942-1943 (Box 37, Folder 16-17)
      - Drake, St. Clair, "General Observations on West Side Families," manuscript, chart, undated (Box 37, Folder 18)
      - Emerson, Helena, "Sibling Rivalry," student paper, 1943, Emerson, Helena, "Sibling Rivalry," chart, 1943 SEE Box 87, Folder 2 (OVERSIZE) (Box 37, Folder 19)
      - Havighurst, Robert J., "Immanent Justice," "Punishments," "Misbehavior," interview questions, 1943 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - National Association for Nursery Education, "Personality Changes in Young Children," manuscript, data sheet, ca. 1937 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Nursery School Populations, "History of Children in Their Families," questionnaires, notes, 1943 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Work Projects Administration, Nursery School Project, manuscripts, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Ames family interviews, Thelma S. Downs, interviewer, transcripts, notes, 1942 (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Davis family interviews, Thelma S. Downs, interviewer, transcripts, notes, 1942 (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - Helm family interviews, Thelma S. Downs, interviewer, transcripts, notes, 1942-1943 (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - Henderson family interviews, Thelma S. Downs, interviewer, transcripts, notes, 1942 (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - Ivory family interviews, Thelma S. Downs, interviewer, transcripts, notes, 1942 (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - Johnson family interviews, Thelma S. Downs, interviewer, transcripts, notes, 1942-1943 (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - King family interviews, Thelma S. Downs, interviewer, transcripts, notes, 1942 (Box 38, Folder 11)
      - McKay family interviews, notes, 1943 (Box 38, Folder 12)
      - McKay family interviews, "Cecil ("the big one") and Cecil Lee ("the little one")," manuscript, undated (Box 38, Folder 13)
      - McKay family interviews, "Level of Aggression and Rivalry," "Rivalry," partial manuscripts, notes, 1944-1949 (Box 38, Folder 14)
      - McKay family interviews, Robert J. Havighurst, "McKay--Comments," notes, undated (Box 38, Folder 15)
      - McKay family interviews, child development charts, notes, 1946 (Box 38, Folder 16)
      - McKay family interviews, medical and psychological analyses, Helen B. Ross, manuscripts, tests, notes, 1943 (Box 38, Folder 17)
      - McKay family interviews, transcripts, 1942-1944 (Box 38, Folder 18-20)
      - McKay family interviews, Thelma S. Downs, interviewer, transcripts, notes, 1942-1943 (Box 38, Folder 21)
      - McKay family interviews, Thelma S. Downs, interviewer, 1942-1943 (Box 39, Folder 1-2)
      - McKay family interviews, Thelma S. Downs, photos, notes, ca. 1943 (Box 39, Folder 3-4)
      - McKay family interviews, St. Clair Drake, interviewer, transcripts, notes, 1943 (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - McKay family interviews, Buena V. Farabee, interviewer, transcripts, notes, 1943-1944 (Box 39, Folder 6-7)
      - McKay family interviews, Dorothy Jones, interviewer, transcripts, transcripts, 1944 (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - McKay family interviews, J. L. Nealy, interviewer, transcripts, 1943 (Box 40, Folder 2)
      - McKay family interviews, Bertha P. Tipton, interviewer, transcripts, notes, 1943 (Box 40, Folder 3)
      - McKay family interviews, excerpts, class--child training, notes, ca. 1943 (Box 40, Folder 4)
      - McKay family interviews, excerpts, class data, notes, 1943 (Box 40, Folder 5)
      - McKay family interviews, excerpts, mother, father, and other trainers, notes, ca. 1943 (Box 40, Folder 6)
      - McKay family interviews, excerpts, Claudette and Ruth, notes, note cards, undated (Box 40, Folder 7)
      - McKay family interviews, excerpts, Cecil and Cecil Lee, notes, ca. 1943 (Box 40, Folder 8)
      - McKay family interviews, excerpts, Harold, notes, ca. 1943 (Box 40, Folder 9)
      - McNiel family interviews, Thelma S. Downs, interviewer, transcripts, notes, 1942-1943 (Box 40, Folder 10)
      - Slanton family interviews, Thelma S. Downs, interviewer, transcripts, notes, 1942 (Box 40, Folder 11)
      - Straton family interviews, Thelma S. Downs, interviewer, transcripts, notes, 1942-1943 (Box 40, Folder 12-13)
    - Sub-subseries 3: Hyde Park Neighborhood House Material
      - Erickson, Martha, "Dissertation Outline," 1944 (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Erickson, Martha, "The Use of Projective Techniques in Personality Study," manuscript, 1943 (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Community notes, "Notes on the Dorchester Beehive Apartments," manuscripts, 1942 (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - Admave family interviews, note cards, undated (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - Admave family interviews, Martha Erickson, interviewer, "Notes on Family History," manuscripts, undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - Admave family interviews, Martha Erickson, "The Case Study of Family X," manuscripts, notes, 1942-1943 (Box 41, Folder 6-10)
      - Admave family interviews, Edward Clifford, "A Case Study of Identification in a Lower Class Family," M.A. Thesis, 1950 (Box 41, Folder 11)
      - Admave family interviews, Vivian Schneiderman, "Some Casual Observations of a Father-Image in a Lower Class Family Study," student paper, undated (Box 41, Folder 12)
      - Admave family interviews, Richard T. Scott, "Case Analysis of Dick--Family X," student paper, 1957 (Box 41, Folder 13)
      - Bender family interviews, M. Chandler, interviewer, transcripts, notes, 1943-1944 (Box 41, Folder 14-16)
      - Breier family interviews, notes, ca. 1973 (Box 42 RESTRICTED, Folder 1)
      - Breier family interviews, analyses, comments, summaries, notes, 1946 (Box 42 RESTRICTED, Folder 2)
      - Breier family interviews, "The Case Study of Family Y," Elizabeth Bott, interviewer, manuscripts, notes, 1945-1946 (Box 42 RESTRICTED, Folder 3-8)
      - Breier family interviews, excerpts, summary of interview cutting, notes, undated (Box 42 RESTRICTED, Folder 9)
      - Breier family interviews, excerpts, history, notes, 1946 (Box 42 RESTRICTED, Folder 10)
      - Breier family interviews, excerpts, material culture, notes, ca. 1945-1946 (Box 43 RESTRICTED, Folder 1-2)
      - Breier family interviews, excerpts, non-material culture, notes, ca. 1945-1946 (Box 43 RESTRICTED, Folder 3)
      - Breier family interviews, excerpts, Mrs. Breier, notes, ca. 1946 (Box 43 RESTRICTED, Folder 4)
      - Breier family interviews, excerpts, Pat, notes, ca. 1946 (Box 43 RESTRICTED, Folder 5-6)
      - Breier family interviews, excerpts, Jackie, notes, ca. 1946 (Box 43 RESTRICTED, Folder 7)
      - Breier family interviews, excerpts, Jimmie, notes, ca. 1946 (Box 43 RESTRICTED, Folder 8)
      - Breier family interviews, excerpts, Sally, notes, 1946 (Box 43 RESTRICTED, Folder 9-10)
      - Breier family interviews, excerpts, Carol, notes, ca. 1945-1950 (Box 43 RESTRICTED, Folder 11)
      - Breier family interviews, Charles E. Bidwell, "Social Factors in the Personality Development of Two Lower Class Children," student paper, 1954 (Box 43 RESTRICTED, Folder 12)
      - Breier family interviews, Elizabeth Bott, "The Breiers," manuscript, outline, correspondence, notes, 1946-1947 (Box 43 RESTRICTED, Folder 13)
      - Breier family interviews, Elizabeth Bott, "The Case of Sally," manuscript, correspondence, notes, 1946 (Box 43 RESTRICTED, Folder 14)
      - Breier family interviews, Elizabeth Bott, "Informal Groups," manuscript, memorandum, 1949 (Box 43 RESTRICTED, Folder 15)
      - Breier family interviews, Lee Rainwater, "Case Study of Sally Briar," student paper, 1949 (Box 43 RESTRICTED, Folder 16)
      - Breier family interviews, Lee Rainwater, Thematic Apperception Tests, Carol and Sally Breier, additional comments by Mrs. Moore, manuscripts, notes, undated (Box 43 RESTRICTED, Folder 17)
      - Breier family interviews, Benjamin Wright, "The Youngest," Carol Breier, manuscript, 1950 (Box 44 RESTRICTED, Folder 1)
      - Kluge family, Martha Erickson, interviewer, transcripts, notes, 1942 (Box 44 RESTRICTED, Folder 2)
      - Marshall-Roti family, Lucile Shepard, "Case Study," manuscript, 1949 (Box 44 RESTRICTED, Folder 3)
      - Marshall-Roti family, Lucile Shepard, interviewer, transcripts, 1949 (Box 44 RESTRICTED, Folder 4)
      - Pellikan family, Martha Erickson, interviewer, transcripts, 1942 (Box 44 RESTRICTED, Folder 5)
      - Rosen family, Martha Erickson, interviewer, transcripts, 1942 (Box 44 RESTRICTED, Folder 6)
      - Smierciak family, Martha Erickson, interviewer, transcripts, 1942 (Box 44 RESTRICTED, Folder 7)
      - Vallone family, Martha Erickson, interviewer, transcripts, notes, 1942-1943 (Box 44 RESTRICTED, Folder 8-10)
  - Subseries 6: Acculturation Project
    - General, guided interview questionnaire, undated (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - General, "The Public Schools and the Acculturation of Working Class Children," manuscript, undated (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - General, "Prospectus of a Comparative Field-Study of the Role of the Schools in the Acculturation of Various Color Groups and Races in the Continental United States, Hawaii, Various Cultures of the Caribbean Islands, and Guatemala," partial manuscript, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Brazil, notes, undated (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - Brazil, correspondence, 1945, 1955 (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - Brazil, reprints, galley proofs, 1952-1955 (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - California, correspondence, 1944-1945 (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - California, calendars, financial statement, notes, 1944 (Box 44, Folder 18-19)
    - California, family and community sketches, notes, undated (Box 44, Folder 20)
    - California, school interviews, manuscripts, memoranda, 1947 (Box 44, Folder 21)
    - California, "The Schools' Most Costly Weakness: the Schools and the Cultural Assimilation of Americans of Negro, mexican, and Chinese Background," manuscript, partial manuscripts, notes, ca. 1944 (Box 45, Folder 1-5)
    - California, "The Public Schools and the Cultural Assimilation of Americans of Negro, Mexican, and Chinese Background," manuscript, 1944 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - California, "Role of the Public Schools in the Acculturation of Mexican and Negro America," partial manuscript, undated (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - California, Nellie Ai-Lei Chao, "Acculturation of the Chinese College Students in the United States," student paper, 1957 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - California, Los Angeles City Junior High School Vice-Principals' Workshop, "Helping Teachers Understand Adolescent Children," manuscript, 1944-1945 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Hawaii, "The Public Schools and America's Most Successful Racial Democracy: Hawaii," manuscripts, notes, ca. 1947 (Box 45, Folder 10-11)
    - Hawaii, Douglas S. Yamamura, "A Study of Some of the Factors in the Education of the Child of Hawaiian Ancestry in Hana, Maui," M.A. thesis, 1941 (Box 45, Folder 12-13)
  - Subseries 7: Intelligence Testing
    - Sub-subseries 1: General
      - Correspondence, 1945-1952 (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, budget and finances, manuscripts, memoranda, notes, 1945-1949 (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, Kenneth Eells, manuscripts, memoranda, notes, 1945-1955 (Box 46, Folder 3-4)
      - Correspondence, Robert D. Hess, notes, 1950-1952 (Box 46, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, University of Chicago Press, contract, 1950-1951 (Box 46, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence, World Book Company, manuscripts, contract, notes, 1950-1959 (Box 46, Folder 7-8)
      - Correspondence, World Book Company, final pictures for Quincy trial, 1951-1952 (Box 46, Folder 9-10)
      - Notes, bibliographies, pamphlet, 1949 (Box 46, Folder 11)
      - Notes, foreign born, 1940 census, undated (Box 46, Folder 12)
      - Notebook, undated (Box 46, Folder 13)
      - Note cards, intelligence--general, other theories of intelligence, undated (Box 46, Folder 14)
      - Note cards, effect of environment on test scores, undated (Box 46, Folder 15)
      - Note cards, effect of motivation on test scores, effect of practice on test scores, undated (Box 46, Folder 16)
      - Note cards, factor analysis--general, two factor analysis, multiple factor analysis, undated (Box 46, Folder 17)
      - Note cards, fluctuations in I. Q., problem solving in children, undated (Box 46, Folder 18)
      - Note cards, research notes, 3" x 5" cards, undated (Box 47)
      - Note cards, research notes, 5" x 7" cards, undated (Box 48)
      - Note cards, research notes, 5" x 7" cards, undated (Box 49)
      - Photographs, impoverished urban environment, undated (Box 50, Folder 1-2)
      - Manuscripts, lectures, notes, undated (Box 50, Folder 3-4)
      - "Children as the Basic Human Resources of the United States in the Building of an Expanding Nation, Society, and Economy," prospectus, ca. 1950 (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - "The Child's Cultural Learning Within the Family," Social Science Research Committee, proposal, memorandum, notes, 1950 (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - "Cultural Groups and Intelligence," manuscripts, notes, undated (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - "Cultural Influences in Intelligence-Tests: Conceptual Framework for Total Research," manuscripts, notes, undated (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - "The Depression of the Lower-Middle Social Class in the American Society," manuscript, undated (Box 50, Folder 9)
      - "Education for the Conservation of the Human Resources of the United States," manuscript, galley proofs, notes, charts, undated (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - "Experimental Study of Cultural Influences," partial manuscript, notes, chart, undated (Box 50, Folder 11)
      - "The General Nature of the Procedure," M. I. T., manuscript, undated (Box 50, Folder 12)
      - "Intelligence and Cultural Differences," "Suggestions for Outline of Proposed Monograph," with Kenneth Eells, Robert J. Havighurst, Virgil E. Herrick, and Ralph W. Tyler, outline, chapters three and four, manuscripts, notes, 1947 (Box 50, Folder 13)
      - "Intelligence Tests Penalize the Low Socio-Economic Groups," with Robert J. Havighurst, manuscript, undated (Box 50, Folder 14)
      - "The Measurement of Mental Systems (Can Intelligence Be Measured?)," with Robert J. Havighurst, manuscripts, notes, ca. 1948 (Box 50, Folder 15-16)
      - Arthur S. Otis, "Can Intelligence Be Measured? A Reply to Davis and Havighurst," Robert J. Havighurst and Allison Davis, "A Rejoinder to Mr. Otis," manuscripts, ca. 1948 (Box 50, Folder 17)
      - "Social Class Influences Upon Socialization and Intelligence," with Robert J. Havighurst, manuscript, undated (Box 50, Folder 18)
      - "Study of the Relationship Between Types of Problems in Two Experimental Tests of Intelligence," with Robert D. Hess, Social Science Research Committee, proposal, 1950 (Box 50, Folder 19)
      - "Suggestions for Research," with Ernest A. Haggard, outline, 1948 (Box 50, Folder 20)
      - "What About I. Q.s," with Robert D. Hess, reprint, undated (Box 50, Folder 21)
      - "What Do Intelligence Tests Measure? (The Cultural Bias in Tests of Intelligence)," with Robert J. Havighurst, manuscripts, notes, undated (Box 50, Folder 22)
      - Baldwin, A. L., "Socialization and the Parent Child Relationship," charts, undated (Box 50, Folder 23)
      - Bergman, Daniel V., "Preliminary Report on Methods of Analysis, Progress, and Qualitative Findings in the Examination of a Sample Tested to Explore the Effects of Social Learning on Manifest Intelligence," manuscript, notes, undated (Box 50, Folder 24)
      - Bergman, Daniel V., "Report on G. E. B. Intelligence Test Research," manuscript, chart, notes, 1952 (Box 50, Folder 25)
      - Bloom, Benjamin S., "Some Major Assumptions Underlying the Development of Intelligence Tests," "A Study of Problem Solving," manuscripts, notes, undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - Boushall, Thomas C., "The Promise and Potential in the Development of America's Greatest Natural Resource," manuscript, 1946 (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - Crain, Robert, "A Reconsideration of the North-Hatt Occupational Prestige Scale," manuscript, undated (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - Eells, Kenneth, "Some Implications for School Practice of the Chicago Studies of Cultural Bias in Intelligence Tests," manuscripts, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - Eells, Kenneth, "Tentative Outline for Dissertation," manuscript, memorandum, notes, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - Gilder, Mary Ellen, "Responses to Frustration Presented in Phantasy with Play Toys," manuscript, undated (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - Haggard, Ernest A., "Influence of Culture Background on Test Performance," "Social-Status and Intelligence," manuscripts, reprint, outline, correspondence, bibliography, notes, 1947-1954 (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - Hess, Robert D., "An Experimental Culture-Fair Test of Mental Ability," Ph.D. dissertation, 1950 (Box 51, Folder 8-9)
      - Hess, Robert D., "An Inquiry into the Relationship Between Personality Patterns and School Performance," "Possible Laboratory Items Relatively Free of Culture Bias," manuscripts, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 10)
      - Hess, Robert D., Thematic Apperception Tests, undated (Box 51, Folder 11)
      - Hurst, T. W., "Analysis of 'Situations from Real Life' Test," memorandum, 1951 (Box 51, Folder 12)
      - Krogman, [?], "What We Don't Know About Race," manuscripts, undated (Box 51, Folder 13)
      - Kraut, Johanna, memorandum, undated (Box 51, Folder 14)
      - Study of Educational Progress, "Test of Educational Progress," college-level, manuscripts, 1952 (Box 51, Folder 15)
      - Weddington, Rachel T., "The Degree of Relationship Between Social-Class and Color-Group Stereotypes in Children," dissertation proposals, questionnaire, charts, analytic instruments, undated (Box 51, Folder 16)
      - Unidentified, "Learning and Instruction," manuscript, 1950 (Box 51, Folder 17)
      - Unidentified, "More Realistic Social Studies," manuscript, undated (Box 51, Folder 18)
      - Unidentified, "Pre-School Project Guided Interview," partial manuscript, 1963 (Box 51, Folder 19)
      - Unidentified, "Problems Expressed by Students During Focused Interviews," manuscript, undated (Box 51, Folder 20)
      - Reprints, clippings, news items, 1941-1952 (Box 51, Folder 21)
    - Sub-subseries 2: School Studies
      - General Education Board, correspondence, memoranda, 1949 (Box 51, Folder 22)
      - General Education Board, tables and analyses, manuscripts, analytic instruments, charts, notes, 1948-1949 (Box 51, Folder 23)
      - General Education Board, "General Education Board Study of Cultural Factors in Intelligence-Tests," with Ralph W. Tyler, Robert J. Havighurst, W. Lloyd Warner, Virgil E. Herrick, manuscript, undated (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - General Education Board, Robert D. Hess, "G. E. B. Intelligence Test Research," manuscripts, tables, 1949 (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Gary Study, analytic instruments, charts, notes, undated (Box 52, Folder 3-4)
      - Gary Study, Roosevelt School Study, questionnaires, ca. 1946-1947 (Box 52, Folder 5-8)
      - Gary Study, Roosevelt School Study, psychological analyses, 1954-1955 (Box 52, Folder 9)
      - Gary Study, Roosevelt School Study, Nancy E. Brandon, "Brief Report of Interviews with Children at Roosevelt School," manuscript, 1947 (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - Gary Study, [Daniel V.] Bergman, manuscripts, outline, memoranda, tables, notes, 1948-1950 (Box 53, Folder 2)
      - Gary Study, Ernest A. Haggard, "Research Report," manuscripts, 1946 (Box 53, Folder 3)
      - Rockford Study, memorandum, paste boards, 1947 (Box 53, Folder 4)
      - Rockford Study, error analysis, memoranda, tables, 1947 (Box 53, Folder 5)
      - Rockford Study, item analysis, correspondence, memorandum, tables, analytic instruments, notes, 1947-1949 (Box 53, Folder 6)
      - Rockford Study, logic and math games, tables, 1948-1949 (Box 53, Folder 7)
      - Rockford Study, Negro-White I. Q.'s, charts, notes, undated (Box 53, Folder 8)
      - Rockford Study, summary, test categories, and analyses, manuscripts, tables, notes, undated (Box 53, Folder 9)
      - Rockford Study, "Article on Rockford Experiment," with Ernest A. Haggard, Robert J. Havighurst, and Virgil E. Herrick, outline, notes, undated (Box 53, Folder 10)
      - Rockford Study, Kenneth Eells, "Explanation of Report on Item Analysis," manuscript, 1946 (Box 53, Folder 11)
      - Rockford Study, Ernest A. Haggard, "Social-Status and Intelligence," manuscript, undated (Box 53, Folder 12)
      - Rockford Study, Charles K. and Marian E. Warriner, "Field Research Report on the Study of Social Class in Rockford, Illinois," manuscript, memorandum, 1945-1946 (Box 53, Folder 13-14)
      - Rockford Study, unidentified, "Proposal for Doctoral Dissertation," manuscripts, undated (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - Sub-subseries 3: Davis Tests
      - "How Do You Work Problems?" test pamphlet, undated (Box 53, Folder 16)
      - "Proposal for the Development and Standardization of a Verbal Test of General Intelligence which Will Measure and Offer a Means of Comparing the Abilities of All Socio-Economic Levels," manuscript, charts, undated (Box 53, Folder 17)
      - "Real-Life Situations," test pamphlet, undated (Box 53, Folder 18)
      - "Study of Cultural Factors in Intelligence: Instructions to the Tester-Interviewer," manuscripts, notes, undated (Box 53, Folder 19)
      - "Validation Projects for Winter Quarter," outline, notes, undated (Box 53, Folder 20)
      - Davis Games, Game One (Junior), Game One--A (Junior and Senior), Game Two (Senior), booklets, notes, 1949-1950 (Box 53, Folder 21)
      - "Davis Test of Intelligence," Manual A, Manual for Game Two (Junior), manuscripts, test questions, undated (Box 53, Folder 22)
      - "Davis Test of Intelligence," Manual B, Manual for Game Two (Senior), manuscript, 1949 (Box 54, Folder 1)
      - "Davis Test of Intelligence," Manual C, Manual for Game One (Junior), manuscript, 1949 (Box 54, Folder 2)
      - "Davis Test of Intelligence," Manual D, Manual for Game One (Senior), manuscript, 1949 (Box 54, Folder 3)
      - "Davis Test of Intelligence," Manual E, Game One--A (Senior), Game One--A (Junior), manuscripts, undated (Box 54, Folder 4)
      - Davis-Eells Test, "Appendix C. Development of Norms," galley proof, undated (Box 54, Folder 5)
      - Davis-Eells Test, "A Comparison of the Performance of Selected Pupils on the Davis-Eells Test, Elementary Level, and the Otis, Quick-Scoring Mental Ability Test," manuscript, undated (Box 54, Folder 6)
      - Davis-Eells Test, "Davis-Eells Test of General Intelligence or Problem-Solving Ability," manual, 1953 (Box 54, Folder 7)
      - Davis-Eells Test, "Description of a Cooperative Program for Standardizing the Davis-Eells Games," manuscript, charts, tables, notes, undated (Box 55, Folder 1)
      - Davis-Eells Test, "Description of a Cooperative Program for Standardizing the Davis-Eells Games," Schools Invited to Participate in the Davis-Eells Games Standardization Program, correspondence, 1949-1952 (Box 55, Folder 2)
      - Davis-Eells Test, "Manual for Davis-Eells Test of General Intelligence," with Kenneth Eells, partial manuscripts, notes, ca. 1953 (Box 55, Folder 3)
      - Davis-Eells Test, Kenneth Eells, "Test Procedures for Teachers," manuscripts, undated (Box 55, Folder 4)
      - Tests V-1 through V-5, Tests P-1 through Test P-10, manuscripts, correspondence, memoranda, booklets, paste books, charts, tables, notes, 1946-1949 (Box 55, Folder 5-11)
      - "Notes for Intelligence Test," manuscripts, sketches, notes, 1945 (Box 56, Folder 1)